Rolland B. Marvin Collection
Rolland B. Marvin Collection
Unknown.
Marvin, Rolland B.
0.75 linear ft.
Books, clippings, notes, memorabilia, relating to the four-term mayor of Syracuse, New York.
2709836
Biographical History
Rolland B. "Rolly" Marvin (?-1979) was a four-term mayor of Syracuse, New York whose terms covered the worst years of the Great Depression (1930-41). As mayer he initiated numerous important projects, among them bringing Carrier Corporation to the city, building a new railroad station and elevating the tracks that formerly ran through the center of downtown, constructing MacArthur Stadium to lure a professional baseball team, and renovating numerous city parks. He served as chair of the Onondaga County Republican Party (1939-1942), was a delegate to the Republican National Conventions of 1940 and 1944, and ran for the New York State Senate (1944).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Rolland B. Mayor Collection contains books, pamphlets, clippings, disc records and other material relating to Rolland B. Marvin and to Syracuse history.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is unprocessed and remains in original order.
Related Material
has numerous holdings relating to politics and government, and to local Central New York and Syracuse history, in both our manuscript and rare books collections. Please refer to for a complete listing of manuscript collections, and to for rare books and published material.
Separated Material
Complete run of the Saturday Night Bugle, transferred to Rare Books for cataloging, 1992. Marvin's four terms as mayor figure prominently in the paper. Please search for this item.
Audiotape of interview with Manny Mannheim, Saturday Night Bugle founder, transferred to Belfer, 1994.
Commercial recordings sent to cataloging.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Politics, government and public administration; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Marvin, Rolland B.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Republican Party (N.Y.); Mayors -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Campaign speeches -- New York (State); Campaign speeches -- United States.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- History.; Books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Memorabilia.; Phonograph records.; Mayors.
Access Restrictions
The collection is currently unprocessed and not available for research. Please contact for more information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles Marvin, 2005.
Inventory
- Speeches
  - Audio recordings
    - Introduction by Mayor Marvin - [Wendell] Willkie speech, marvin_rb_001; 1 lacquer disc
    - Let's Hear the Record!, marvin_rb_002-003; 2 copies, shellac disc; text from speeches by candidate Franklin D. Roosevelt, during his third campaign, spoken by unknown voice actor, released on Gotham Record Company recording 76468
    - Saturday Night Speech, 11/02/1940; marvin_rb_004; 1 lacquer disc
    - [Wendell] Willkie Speech, Madison Square Garden, parts 1-8, 11/02/1940; marvin_rb_005-008; 4 lacquer discs
    - Thomas E. Dewey, 11/02/1940; marvin_rb_009; 1 lacquer disc
    - George Parsons, 10/29/1940; marvin_rb_010; 1 lacquer disc
    - Irwin S. Cobb, parts 1-7, marvin_rb_011-014; 4 lacquer discs
    - Young Republican’s Club’s Speech At Hamilton, NY, parts 1 and 2, 05/15/1942; marvin_rb_015-016; 2 lacquer discs
    - Testimonial Dinner at Hotel Syracuse, parts 1-7, 02/03/1942; marvin_rb_017-020; 4 lacquer discs
    - Claire Booth for Willkie, marvin_rb_021-022; 2 copies, shellac disc
    - Mayor Rolland B. Marvin - Introduction and Speech, Madison Square Garden, parts 1-9, 11/02/1940; marvin_rb_023-027; 5 lacquer discs